David Kavaler

dmkavaler@ucdavis.edu

Overview

I am experienced in data analysis, including data mining, data gathering, statistical modeling (including predictive and explanatory models), metric design, natural language processing, and machine learning. I have extensive experience in gathering data and using R and Python to build both predictive and explanatory statistical models, and I am an adept programmer in multiple languages. My primary interests are in the fields of data analysis, data mining, empirical software engineering, and security.

Education

09/2013 to Present UC Davis, Ph.D. in Computer Science

09/2009 to 06/2013 UC Davis, B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

Publications

Stochastic Actor-Oriented Modeling for Studying Homophily and Social Influence in OSS Projects. ★

David Kavaler, Vladimir Filkov. Empirical Software Engineering (2016): 1-29. dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10664-016-9431-y.

★ Invited to present at SIGSOFT International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE) 2016.

Using and Asking: APIs Used in the Android Market and Asked About in Stack Overflow. ☆

<u>David Kavaler</u>, Daryl Posnett, Clint Gibler, Hao Chen, Prem Devanbu, and Vladimir Filkov. Presented at 5th International Conference on Social Informatics (SocInfo). *Social Informatics*. Springer International Publishing, 2013. 405418.

☆ Best Paper Nominee.

Pending Publications

When Stack Overflow Slows Down: Latency of Answers to Questions About New Android APIs. (Working Title) David Kavaler, Vladimir Filkov

Exploiting Time and Subject Locality for Fast, Efficient, and Understandable Alert Triage.

David Kavaler, Michael Bierma, Corey Hudson

Awards and Recognitions

Dean's List Letters and Science and Engineering: Fall 2009, Spring 2011, Fall 2011, Winter 2012,

Spring 2012, Fall 2012

A+ Grade Received Introduction to Software Engineering, Embedded Systems, Modern Physics, General

Chemistry, Elementary Accounting

Graduate Level GPA 4.0

Fellowships Awarded UC Davis Graduate Group in Computer Science Fellowship: Fall 2013, Spring 2015,

Fall 2015

Best Paper Nominations International Conference on Social Informatics (SocInfo) 2013

Invited Presentations SIGSOFT International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE) 2016

Employment and Research Experience

Fall 2013 - Present Computer Science Department - Teaching Assistant and Research Assistant in DECAL lab

with Premkumar Devanbu and Vladimir Filkov

June 2016 - September 2016 Cybersecurity Research Intern (Summer) at Sandia National Labs

Summer 2010 Engineering Intern at Sensys Networks

Programming Languages, Software Tools and Operating Systems

R, Java, C, C++, Python, SQL, JavaScript, bash, x86 Assembly, LaTeX, ActionScript / Flash

PostgreSQL, Node.js, Angular.js, Eclipse IDE, Git, Android SDK, Unity, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator Packages and functions: scikit-learn, base R, data.table, (g)lm, (g)lmer, ggplot, pscl, MASS, car, dplyr Ubuntu, Fedora, Android, Windows

References

Vladimir Filkov Professor. Computer Science Department, UC Davis. filkov@cs.ucdavis.edu Premkumar Devanbu Professor. Computer Science Department, UC Davis. devanbu@cs.ucdavis.edu